Guide to the Blukis Onat Applied Sciences (BOAS), Inc. Papers 1968-2010
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Sites 45KI737 (Old Pine Street), 45KI688 (Seattle Industrial District Landfill also called Maintenance Base) and 45KI00820 (McClellan Station Landfill) and Locations Identified as Moderate and High Probability for Cultural Resources, Archaeological Monitoring during Construction Phase Excavations of the Central Link Light Rail Project (CLLR), King County: data CDs with aerial photos, maps, and artifacts; black and white print; correspondence; 103 progress reports (2002-2006); field notes; project maps; site forms and NRHP nomination forms; stratigraphic profiles; and reports., 2002-2008 (Box-folder 39/1-4, Project 200005.C)
- BOAS Ethnographic and Traditional Cultural Properties Study for CLLR, King County: black-and-white historic photographs; color prints; correspondence; Epic of the Winds Traditional Cultural Property National Register of Historic Places documents; and Winds, Waterways, and Weirs report., 2001-2004 (Box-folder 39/5-8, Project 200005.D)
- BOAS Ethnographic and Traditional Cultural Properties Study for Central Link Light Rail Project (CLLR), King County: data CD with oral history transcripts from 2002 interviews with Muckleshoot tribal members., 2001-2004 (Box-folder 69R/1, Project 200005.D)
- Administrative Documents for Central Link Light Rail Project (CLLR): BOAS proposal and qualifications package for archaeological monitoring, traditional cultural properties and ethnographic study for CLLR (2000); correspondence (1999-2005, 2007); CLLR Final Environmental Impact Statement Executive Summary, technical reports, addendum (1999, 2001); Environmental Assessment Initial Segment (2002); and miscellaneous Sound Transit and Regional Transit Authority documents., undated, 1996, 1999-2005, 2007 (Box-folder 40/1-5, Project 200005.E)
- BOAS Archaeological Monitoring and Treatment Plan for University Link Segment in North Link, Central Link Light Rail Transportation Project, King County: CLLR Final Environmental Impact Statement North Link Technical Report (2006); correspondence with geotechnical results; field notes; and report, including data CD copy., 2006-2009 (Box-folder 40/6, Project 200005.F)
- King County Swanson Homes Private Property Development Project and Site 45KI495, Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project, Cultural Resource Assessments: color prints and negatives; field notes; site form; and letter reports., 2000 (Box-folder 41/1-2, Project 200007, 200008)
- Marymoor Park, Sammamish River Restoration Project, Archaeological Considerations during Rechannelization, King County: aerial photograph and copies of historic aerial photos (1956, 1960, 1974, 1977, 1982); correspondence; copies of historic documents, maps, and photographs (1897, 1907-1908, 1950, 1963); project maps; and reports., undated, 1897, 1907-1908, 1950, 1956, 1960, 1963, 1974, 1977, 1982, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 41/3-4, Project 200009.1 and 200009.2)
- Site 45SK239 and Bayview Pipeline Trench, Cultural Resources Monitoring For Department of Public Works, Skagit County: photo CD; correspondence; and letter report., 2000 (Box-folder 41/5, Project 200010)
- Proposed Lilliwaup Post Office Relocation, Archaeological Survey, Kitsap County: color prints and negatives; field notes; project map; and letter report., 2000 (Box-folder 41/6, Project 200011)
- Proposed Washington State Department of Transportation Park and Ride Facility at Terry's Corner and Roadway Improvements, Camano Island, Cultural Resources Survey, Island County: color prints, negatives, and photo log; correspondence; copies of historic maps (1859 and 1877); project maps; site forms; and original and bound report., 1859, 1877, 2000, 2001 (Box-folder 41/7, Project 200012)
- Longview Mint Farm Industrial Park Development, Cultural Resources Assessment including Coffin Rock (Mt. Coffin) Site 45CW3 and Monitoring Plan, Cowlitz County: data CD; correspondence; copies of historic photographs of Coffin Rock site (1925, 1995); field notes; maps; notes on interviews with local informants; and report., 1925, 1995, 2000, 2001 (Box-folder 41/8-9, Project 200014.1, 200014.2 (see also 200016))
- Proposed Property Development on Swinomish Reservation, Cultural Resources Survey, Skagit County: copies of photographs; map; and letter report., 2001 (Box-folder 41/10, Project 200015)
- Longview Mint Farm Generation Project, Cultural Resources Survey and Assessment, Cowlitz County: data CD; field notes; notes on interviews with local informants; and reports., 2001 (Box-folder 41/11-12, Project 200016.1, 200016.2 (see 200014))
- Cultural Resources Expertise Report for the I-405 Corridor Program Draft EIS Prepared by CH2MHill, Review of the Report by BOAS, Inc., King County: letter review and original CH2MHill report., 2001 (Box-folder 42/1, Project 200102)
- Site 45KI498 and Auburn Commuter Rail Station Garage, Archaeological Field Inspection, Testing, and Monitoring, King County: 1 3.5 inch floppy disk presumably with site form and report; color prints, negatives, and photo log; correspondence; field notes; site form; and reports., 2001 (Box-folder 42/2, Project 200103.1, 200103.2)
- Proposed Goldenrod Bridge Construction Project, Burlington, Cultural Resources Investigation, Skagit County: photo log; correspondence; field notes; and report., 2001 (Box-folder 42/3, Project 200104)
- Site 45KI503 and Kent Commuter Rail Station Garage, Cultural Resources Monitoring, King County: data CD with site form and report; color prints and negatives; copies of historic maps (1910); field notes; site form; and letter report., 2001 (Box-folder 42/4, Project 200105)
- Muckleshoot Indian Tribe Proposed Tribal Health Clinic Expansion and Adjoining Parcel, Cultural Resources Investigation, King County: color prints, negatives, and photo log; correspondence; field notes; letter report; and bound report., 2001 (Box-folder 42/5-6, Project 200106.1, 200106.2)
- Proposed Xwechi'exen, Cherry Point, BP Cogeneration Facility Project, Cultural Resources Investigation for Access Roads and Facility, Whatcom County: 2 data CDs with site form and reports; field notes; and reports., 2002 (Box-folder 42/7-8, Project 200107.1, 200107.2)
- Tacoma Link Light Rail Route including Fife Block (45PI491), Archaeological Monitoring of Probable Areas of Cultural Materials for Sound Transit, Pierce County: color prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes with photo log; National Register and Tacoma Register of Historic Places nomination forms for Fife Block; site form., 2001-2002 (Box-folder 42/9, Project 200110.1, 200110.2)
- Tacoma Link Light Rail Route including Fife Block (45PI491), Archaeological Monitoring of Probable Areas of Cultural Materials for Sound Transit, Pierce County: data CD and reports., 2001-2002 (Box-folder 43/1, Project 200110.1, 200110.2)
- Proposed Airpark Industries Auto Storage Facility, Arlington, Cultural Resources Investigation for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives; field notes; photo log; and report., 2001 (Box-folder 43/2, Project 200112)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS16, Archaeological Survey, Island County: copies of photographs; correspondence; field notes; site form; and letter report., 2001 (Box-folder 43/3, Project 200114)
- Shell Midden and 45WH62, Archaeological Investigation for Lummi Business Council, Whatcom County: color prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; photo log; site form; and letter report., 2001 (Box-folder 43/4, Project 200116)
- Swinomish Marina Project and Cultural Resources especially 45SK225, Cultural Resources Monitoring and Treatment Plan during Marina Construction, Skagit County: report., 2003 (Box-folder 43/5, Project 200202 (see also 199602))
- Green River Trail Phase II, Cultural Resource Survey Update, King County: report., March 2003 (Box-folder 43/6, Project 200203.1 (see 199501))
- Cecil Moses Memorial Park Estuary (formerly North Wind's Weir Park), Archaeological Resources Monitoring under subcontract with MacLeod Reckord, King County: correspondence and 8-page report., 2003 (Box-folder 43/7, Project 200203.2 (see also 199501))
- Green River Trail and Site 45KI680 Jeffs Farm, National Register of Historic Places (NRHP) Registration Form, King County: NRHP form., undated (Box-folder 43/8, Project 200203.3 (see also 199501))
- Green River Trail Phase II between Kent and Auburn, Cultural Resource Survey, King County: artifacts (1 bead, shell, 1 lithic); data CD (200203.1, 200203.2, and 200302.3); field notes (1995 and 2003); project maps; undated review of 1995 BOAS work; color prints and negatives with photo log; and correspondence., undated, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 43/9, Project 200203 (see also 199501) 200203.1, 200203.2, 200302.3)
- Green River Trail Phase II between Kent and Auburn, Cultural Resource Survey, King County: MacLeod Reckord Landscape Architects Project Maps., 2002 (Box-folder 76/8, Project 200203.1)
- Cecil Moses Memorial Park Estuary (formerly North Wind's Weir Park), Archaeological Resources Monitoring, King County: MacLeod Reckord Landscape Architects Project Maps and copy of 1907 Duwamish-Puyallup Survey Map., 1907, 2002 (Box-folder 76/9, Project 200203.2)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS17, Archaeological Survey, Island County: correspondence; field notes; and letter report., 2002 (Box-folder 43/10, Project 200204)
- Proposed Granite Falls Alternative Route, Granite Falls, Archaeological Field Investigation Results, Snohomish County: preliminary and bound and unbound final reports., 2002-2003 (Box-folder 44/1-2, Project 200205.1, 200205.2)
- Private Property Development Project and Site 45SN331, Bothell, Cultural Resource Assessment, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives with photo log; correspondence; field notes; site form; and letter report., 2002 (Box-folder 44/3, Project 200207)
- Natural Gas Pipeline and 45IS8, Camano Island, Cultural Resources Assessment, Island County: letter report., 2002 (Box-folder 44/4, Project 200208)
- Goodwin Lake Community Park, Cultural Resource Assessment for Department of Parks and Recreation, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives; field notes; and report., 2003 (Box-folder 44/5, Project 200210)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS16, Cultural Resource Assessment, Island County: project maps and letter report., 2003 (Box-folder 44/6, Project 200301)
- SR 2/Sultan Basin Road Improvements Project, City of Sultan, Cultural Resources Assessment, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives with photo CD; letter report., 2003 (Box-folder 44/7, Project 200302)
- Private Property Development and Tsi-Litch (45WH216), Removal of Human Remains from Two Burials, Blukis Onat Representative of Lummi Indian Business Council, Whatcom County: original and bound report., 2003 (Box-folder 44/8, Project 200303)
- Soos Creek Trail, Cultural Resources Investigations, King County: color prints and negatives; field notes; geotechnical study; historic research documents; project maps; and report., 2003 (Box-folder 44/9, Project 200305)
- Site 45SN308 and Jackson Gulch Road Maintenance Excavations, Archaeological Monitoring for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives; field notes; maps; initial field inspection and final reports., 2003-2004 (Box-folder 44/10, Project 200306.01)
- Sites 45SN28, 45SN303, and 45SN360 and the Proposed Granite Falls Alternate Route, Granite Falls, Archaeological Field Investigations for Stormwater Facilities and Right-of-Way Changes, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives with photo log; correspondence including tribes consulted; Department of Public Works documents; field notes; copy of 1917 Sanborn map for Granite Falls; copies of 2004 news releases; project maps/aerial photographs; initial field inspection and final reports., 1917, 2002-2005 (Box-folder 45/1-4, Project 200306.2, 200306.2a)
- Grobe and Norman Cottages, Chatham Acres Country Club, Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) and Historic American Engineering Record (HAER) Documentation for Floodplain Mitigation, Snohomish County: data CD with photos and logs; black and white prints; correspondence; maps; Grove Cottage HABS/HAER documents and Norman Cottage HABS/HAER documents., 2004 (Box-folder 45/5, Project 200306.03)
- Multiple Department of Public Works (DPW) Projects, Screening for Known Sites and Monitoring for Archaeological Resources, Snohomish County: correspondence; DPW permits; and letter reports., 2003-2005 (Box-folder 45/6-7, Project 200306.04a, 200306.04b)
- Granite Falls Bridge No. 102 Rehabilitation, Cultural Resource Inventory, Snohomish County: 3 data CDs with photos; color prints and negatives; photo log; HAER documents on bridge; historic research including copies of multiple newspaper articles from 1934 completion of bridge; and original and bound report. (Box-folder 45/8, Project 200306.05)
- Proposed Wetland Mitigation Sites for SR 524 Improvements, Archaeological Field Investigations for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: original and bound report., 2004 (Box-folder 45/9, Project 200306.07)
- Proposed Wetland Mitigation Sites for SR 524 Improvements, Archaeological Field Investigations for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives; and field notes. (Box-folder 46/1, Project 200306.07)
- 192nd Street Northwest Drainage Improvements and Site 45SN4, Isolates 45SN375, 376, and 377, Warm Beach, Archaeological Monitoring of Excavations for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: artifact (glass bead); color prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; and letter report., 2004 (Box-folder 46/2, Project 200306.08)
- Skykomish Slough Bridge No. 150 Replacement (200306.09) and Little Pilchuck Creek Bridge No. 601 and Fish Passage Complex (fish ladder, overflow weir, and dam) Historic Site (2000306.10), Cultural Resource Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: field notes; site form; and original and bound reports., 2004-2005 (Box-folder 46/3-4, Project 200306.09 200306.10)
- Site 45SN13 and Proposed Twin Rivers Confluence Reach Restoration, Archaeological Field Investigations Results for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: aerial photos/project maps; correspondence; field notes; site form; and original and bound report., 2004-2005 (Box-folder 46/5, Project 200306.12)
- Sauk River Bridge No. 414 Replacement and Marten Creek Bridge No. 562 Replacement and Camp Silverton and Monte Cristo Railroad Historic Sites, Cultural Resource Inventory for Department of Public Works, Snohomish County: correspondence; data CD with Marten Creek report; USDA-Forest Service site forms; and Sauk River report., 2003, 2005 (Box-folder 46/6-7, Project 200306.16 200306.18 (see also 200601.08))
- Valterra View Estates Private Property Development, Cultural Resources Inventory and Archaeological Field Investigations Results, Snohomish County: data CD; color prints and negatives; correspondence; field notes; copies of historic documents (1895, 1910, 1913); photo log; project maps; original and bound reports., 2003-2004 (Box-folder 46/8, Project 200309)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS9, Review of Cultural Resources and Archaeological Survey, Island County: data CD with photos; and letter reports., 2004-2005 (Box-folder 46/9, Project 200310 200310a)
- City of Covington’s SR 516/Wax Road to Jenkins Creek Access Management Improvements Project, Cultural Resources Investigations, King County: correspondence; field notes; project maps; and letter reports., 2000, 2004 (Box-folder 47/1, Project 200401 200401a)
- Site 45IS12 and Juniper Beach Water District's Proposed Water System Improvements Project, Camano Island, Archaeological Field Investigations Report, Island County: color prints and negatives; field notes; project maps; site form; letter report and original and bound report., 2001, 2003, 2004 (Box-folder 47/2, Project 200402 200402a)
- Site 45IS12 and Juniper Beach Water District's Proposed Water System Improvements Project, Camano Island, Archaeological Field Investigations Report, Island County: 1 box artifacts (wood debris, midden bones, other faunal remains, lithics)., 2004 (Box-folder 72/4, Project 200402)
- Site 45SN145 and Olympic Pipe Line Company's Ebey Island Reroutes, Cultural Resources Inventory and Archaeological Resources Monitoring of Excavations with Treatment Plan, Snohomish County: 3 data CDs with photos and report; color prints and negatives; correspondence; project maps; and reports., 2004-2005 (Box-folder 47/3-4, Project 200403 200403a)
- Site 45KI724 and City of Carnation Sewer Collection and Conveyance System and King County's Carnation Wastewater Treatment Facility, Cultural Resources Investigations and Archaeological Resources Monitoring of Construction and Geotechnical Excavations and Treatment Plan, Radiocarbon Analysis Results, and Archaeological Data Recovery Results for 45KI1724, King County: color prints and photo CD; data Cd for 45KI1724; correspondence; cultural resources handouts for construction personnel; drilling stratigraphic profiles; field notes; project and topographic maps; and reports., 2003-2009 (Box-folder 69R/2-9, Project 200404/200508 200404.1, 200404.2, 200404.3 200410.01, 200410.02, 200508.01, 200508.02)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS48, Review of Cultural Resources and Archaeological Survey, Island County: letter report., 2004 (Box-folder 47/5, Project 200405)
- Olympic Pipeline Company’s 60th Street Southeast Inspection, Cultural Resources Investigations, Snohomish County: report., 2004 (Box-folder 47/6, Project 200406)
- SR 2 at 5th Street Intersection Improvements Project for City of Sultan, Cultural Resources Investigations, Snohomish County: color prints and negatives; field notes; and letter report., 2004 (Box-folder 47/7, Project 200407)
- Olympic Pipeline Company’s Reroute at Colony Creek, Cultural Resources Investigations, Skagit County: communication and report., 2004 (Box-folder 47/8, Project 200408)
- Buckley (City) Private Property Development, Archaeological Assessment, Pierce County: report., 2004 (Box-folder 47/9, Project 200409)
- Various Wastewater-related Projects and Sites, Cultural Resources Investigations and Archaeological Resources Monitoring for Department of Natural Resources and Parks, Wastewater Treatment Division, King County: photo CD: field notes; reports., 2005-2006 (Box-folder 47/10-12, Project 200410.03, 200410.04, 200410.05)
- Various Wastewater-related Projects and Sites 45KI428 and 45KI429 (200410.08), Cultural Resources Investigations and Archaeological Resources Monitoring for Department of Natural Resources and Parks, Wastewater Treatment Division, King County: correspondence; data CD; field notes; project maps; and reports., 2006-2008 (Box-folder 48/1-8, Project 200410.06-200410.06-11, 200410.14)
- Whidbey Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45IS89, Review of Cultural Resources and Archaeological Survey, Island County: letter report., 2004 (Box-folder 48/9, Project 200411)
- Lopez Island Private Property Improvement Project and Site 45SJ371, Review of Cultural Resources and Archaeological Survey, San Juan County: data CD with report and photos; project map; letter report., 1984, 2004 [sic], 2005 (Box-folder 48/10-11, Project 200501.01, 200501.02)
- Ebey Island and Ebey Slough Transmission and Pipeline Projects, Cultural Resources Inventory and Archaeological Resources Monitoring and Treatment Plan, Snohomish County: photo CD and reports., 2005 (Box-folder 48/12-13, Project 200502.01, 200502.02)
- Centennial Trail Phase II and Sites 45SN365, 45SN378, 45SN379, 45SN382, 45SN384, and 45SN385, Cultural Resources Preliminary Survey, Snohomish County: background documents; field notes; project maps; site inventory forms; and report., 2004-2006 (Box-folder 48/14, Project 200503)
- Camano Island Private Property Improvement Project, Cultural Resources Survey, Island County: project map and letter report., 2005 (Box-folder 49/1, Project 200504)
- Northern Pacific Railway Abandoned Crossing on SR 903 near Roslyn, Cultural Resources Inventory, Kittitas County: CD with correspondence, site form, report and photos; and paper report., 2005 (Box-folder 49/2, Project 200505)
- Bridgeport Way Improvements in City of Lakewood, Cultural Resources Inventory, Pierce County: report., 2006 (Box-folder 49/3, Project 200506)
- Lopez Island Private Property Improvement Project and Sites 45SJ371 and 45SJ185, Review of Cultural Resources and Archaeological Survey, San Juan County: letter report., 2005 (Box-folder 49/4, Project 200509)
- Site 45SK31 and Tallawhalt Housing Development, Cultural Resource Assessment, Swinomish Indian Tribal Community, Skagit County: report., 2006 (Box-folder 49/5, Project 200510)
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement and HOV Project, including the Miller Street Landfill site (45KI760), Environmental Impact Statement Technical Appendices, Ethnohistoric and Geoarchaeological Study, and Archaeological Field Investigations for the Washington State Department of Transportation, King County: 5 CDs with oral history transcripts for Merle Barr and Gilbert KingGeorge interviews, reports, photos, and images (archival); field notes; and print reports., 2004-2007 (Box-folder 49/6-8, Project 200511.01)
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement and HOV Project, including the Miller Street Landfill site (45KI760), Ethnohistoric and Geoarchaeological Study and Archaeological Field Investigations for the Washington State Department of Transportation, King County: Oral History Interviews (2006) of Merle Barr Sr. (Muckleshoot) and Gilbert KingGeorge (Muckleshoot), printed transcripts and 3 1/8" tape Standard Audio cassettes; 8x10" photo from WSU MASC Pratsch collection., undated, 2006 (Box-folder 79/21, Project 200511.01)
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement, Proposed Pontoon Construction Site at Port of Grays Harbor Industrial Development District (IDD) Parcel No. 1 in Hoquiam, IDD Cultural Resource Preliminary Discipline Report for the Washington State Department of Transportation, Grays Harbor County: report., 2006 (Box-folder 50/1, Project 200511.02)
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement, Proposed Pontoon Construction Site at Port of Grays Harbor Industrial Development District (IDD) Parcel No. 1 in Hoquiam, IDD Cultural Resource Preliminary Discipline Report for the Washington State Department of Transportation, Grays Harbor County: Northwest Indian Oral History Collection Interview Descriptions for Tapes 1-55, paper; background research photocopies; 4 data CDs with files and draft and final report (200511.02); 1 data CD with Landau Associates Geotechnical & Hydrogeologic Study of Grays Harbor; 1 photo CD with historical images of Hoquiam River from Polson Museum; and 1 DVD "Traditional Materials for Skokomish Baskets" videos featuring Emily Miller, Louisa Pulsifer and Bruce Miller., undated, 2004-2007 (Box-folder 79/22, Project 200511.02, 200511.02a, 200511.03)
- SR 520 Corridor, Bridge Replacement, Proposed Pontoon Construction Site at Port of Grays Harbor Industrial Development District (IDD) Parcel No. 1, Hoquiam, including 45GH130, IDD Cultural Resource Study and Shoreline Reconnaissance Survey for the Washington State Department of Transportation, Grays Harbor County: bound report includes cultural resource study and shoreline reconnaissance survey in Appendix A (200511.02a) and CD with Appendix F of stratigraphic profiles., 2007 (Box-folder 50/2, Project 200511.02a, 200511.03)